JU LIN

 $+64 \cdot 027 \cdot 545 \cdot 3988 \diamond soasme@gmail.com$ Github: soasme \diamond Blog: www.soasme.com

SUMMARY

Ju Lin has a wide knowledge of web application, DevOps and system administration. He is an expert in Python Programming, Operating System, and Unix Networking. He is a passionate learner with endless curiosity and enjoys jumping out of the comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE

Lipinshuo, Inc

May 2015 - September 2016

Beijing, China

Tech Lead, Software Engineer

- · Project leadership and management. Capable of leading high performing teams under tough deadlines, to meet expectations of multiple customers externally or internally.
- · System administration. Maintained configurations for Nginx, supervisord, gunicorn, etc.
- · System architecture. Developed gateway and message queue applications to improve both the scale and the performance of the entire system.
- · Continuous Delivery. Wrote packaging tool Beeper and deploying tool Fapistrano.
- · Migrated image format from JPEG to WEBP. Reduced CDN bandwidth by 75%.
- · Developed a fully functional e-shop web application that drove 1k+ orders everyday.
- · Developed a spider application to scrap production information in other websites.

Douban Read

April 2013 - March 2015

11p111 =0

Product Development Engineer

Beijing, China

- · Designed and implemented a new version of robust, testable, document-autogen APIs. Reduced network calls by 30%.
- · Extracted ORM manipulations with built-in cache mechanism. Reduced model codes by 50%.
- · Wrote hundreds of py.test fixtures and thousands of test cases. Improved code coverage by 20%.
- · Maintained tens of CI jobs within Jenkins.

Douban Book

June 2012 - April 2013

Beijing, China

Product Development Engineer

- · Participated on the rebuilding & refactoring process of *Douban Book*, which was visited by millions of users everyday. Decoupled this system from a monolithic one, to archive independent deployment.
- · Replaced PTL template engine with Mako. Reduced codes by tens of thousands of lines.
- · Implemented a system synchronizing product price and inventory from almost all e-bookshops in China, such as AmazonCN, Jingdong, Dangdang, etc. There were nearly 16 million+ subjects updating everyday.

Please refer to my LinkedIn profile for the complete list of work experience and references.

http://www.linkedin.com/in/linju

EDUCATION

Jimei University

September 2008 - June 2012

Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Python, Javascript, Java, C

Protocols TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, WSGI

APIs REST, SOAP, JSON, XML

Databases MySQL, Sqlite, Redis, Mongodb, Beansdb Python Web Frameworks Flask, Django, Tornado, Quixote, Celery

Python ORMs DjangoORM, SQLAlchemy

Python Web Runtimes Supervisord, Gunicorn, uWSGI, Nginx

Javascript Frameworks Angular, React & Redux

VCS Git, SVN

CIs Jenkins, TravisCI

Editors Emacs, Vim, SublimeText, Atom